PyPi also known as
PyPI 也被称为
the Python Package Index is a repository where Python packages are stored.
Python Package Index (Python 软件包索引) 是 Python 软件包的存储库
When you pip install a package you are downloading and installing files from PyPi.
当你 pip install 软件包时 会从 PyPI 上下载文件并安装
Anyone can upload a package to PyPi.
所有人都可以向 PyPI 上传软件包
I'm going to show you the basics of how to do it.
我将展示一下上传软件包的基本操作
The PyPi website actually has a test repository as well as the regular repository.
PyPI 网站除了常规的存储库 实际上还有一个测试存储库
This is the test repository website.
这是测试存储库的网站
I'd suggest first uploading your package to
我建议先将软件包上传到测试存储库
the test repository to make sure everything works as
确保所有内容都符合预期之后
expected then you can upload the package to the regular repository on this website.
再将软件包上传到这个网站上的常规存储库
Remember that anybody can download and
请记住 如果软件包在常规存储库中
install your package if it's in the regular repository.
所有人都可以下载安装
The first step is to create an account on PyPi and the TestPyPi repositories.
第一步是分别在 PyPI 和 TestPyPI 存储库中创建账号
If you go to each website,
进入到每个网站
you can click on Register and make an account.
你可以点击 Register (注册) 来创建账号
I've already done this so I'm going to skip this step.
我已经创建过了 所以跳过这个步骤
Next, go to your terminal and enter the directory with your package files.
接下来 进入你的终端 输入你的软件包文件所在目录
Let's open this dsnd probability folder where the package is located.
我们来打开 dsnd_probability 文件夹 也就是软件包所在目录
You'll see that there are a few extra files than
你会看到多了一些额外的文件
what was originally in the package you are working with before.
除了之前在软件包中编写的文件
You'll need to add these extra files.
你需要添加这些额外的文件
The first one is a file called license.txt.
第一个是 license.txt 文件
Opening that file, this is where you put copyright information.
打开这个文件 其中存放了版权信息
I've used the language for the MIT license which
我使用的是从 openource.org 网站复制和粘贴的 MIT 许可证
Next, you'll also need to add a README.md MD file.
接下来 你还需要添加一个 README.md 文件
I haven't filled out this file with enough detail
我还没有在其中补充足够的详细信息
yet but this is where you would document how your package works.
你需要在其中介绍软件包的功能
Finally, create a file called setup.cfg.
最后创建一个 setup.cfg 文件
All you need to put in here is some data about the name of your README file.
你需要在此处输入的是有关 README 文件名称的数据
Let's go back up one level and open the setup.py file.
返回上一级目录 打开 setup.py 文件
You can see I've named my package dsnd_probability.
你可以看到我的软件包命名是 dsnd_probability
The folder with all the package files is also called dsnd_probability.
包含软件包所有文件的文件夹名称也是 dsnd_probability
If you want to upload this code to PyPi,
如果你想要将这些代码上传到 PyPI
you'll need to come up with a different name.
你需要想一个别的名字
Every package on PyPi needs a unique name.
PyPI 的每个软件包都要有一个独一无二的名称
In the setup.py file in
在 setup.py 文件中
the package's variable use the same name that you put in the name variable.
package 变量需要使用 name 变量一样的名称
I'm keeping zip_safe to false
我将 zip_safe 设置为 False
because it means that the package can't be run directly from a zip file.
这意味着无法从 zip 文件中直接运行软件包
This is especially important if you're packages
如果你的软件包依赖需要解压缩
rely on data files that need to remain unzipped for use.
才能使用的数据文件 这一点尤为重要
Again, note as well that I've changed the name of
再次注意 我更改了
the package folder to match dsnd_probability.
软件包文件夹的名称以匹配 dsnd_probability
I'm going to do a bit of hand-waving here.
我在这里的解释比较简略
Though, if you want to read more about how to upload a PyPi,
不过如果你想要了解更多关于如何上传到 PyPI 的内容
I'll include a link to the documentation.
可以参考下方的文档链接
Go to your terminal window and make sure that within
打开你的终端 确保终端处于
terminal you're inside the folder with your package files,
软件包文件所在目录下
then type python setup.py sdist.
输入 python setup.py sdist
If you look at the package folder,
如果查看软件包文件夹
there are now a couple of new folders that appeared.
会看到现在出现了几个新的文件夹
Inside the dist folder is a tar.gz
在 dist 文件夹中是一个 tar.gz 文件
file that you're going to end up uploading to the PyPi repository.
最终会上传到 PyPI 存储库
Next, go back to the terminal and install the twine package with pip install
接下来 返回终端使用 pip install twine 安装 twine 软件包
twine and then type the following command
输入以下命令
to upload the package to the PyPi test repository.
将软件包上传到 PyPI 测试存储库
It's twine upload --repository-url
twine upload --repository-url https://test.pypi.org/legacy/ dist/*
This is what it looks like. Hit Enter.
就是这样 点击回车
That's for my username.
这是我的用户名
This is the username for the TestPyPi repository and my password.
TestPyPI 存储库的用户名 以及我的密码
So, it's giving me an error that says I'm using the same version that I uploaded before.
出现了一个报错 提示我上传的版本号跟之前的版本一样
So, I'm just going to change this from 1.2 to say 1.3.
所以我需要把 1.2 修改为 1.3
You might end up having this error as well and having to do the same thing.
你有可能也会遇到这样的报错 需要做相同的操作
This is because I've already tried to upload this package before with the same version.
这是因为我已经尝试上传过相同的版本
So, I'm going to go back and I'm going to delete
所以我要回到上一层
this dist folder and this extra info folder that were created
删除 dist 文件夹和之前创建的额外的 info 文件夹
before and now I'm going to repeat the same steps, python setup.py sdist.
然后重复之前相同的步骤 python setup.py sdist
I'm going to try again. Twine upload --repository-url.
再次尝试 twine upload --repository-url
Enter my username and my password.
输入我的用户名密码
This time it looks like it worked.
这次看起来成功了
I'm going to go to the TestPyPi website for a second.
我要去 TestPyPI 网站看一下
I'm going to log into my account and it looks like everything uploaded correctly.
登录我的账号 看起来都上传好了
Let's go back to terminal for a second.
再回到终端看一下
I can now actually pip install this package using
现在我就可以使用 pip 安装这个包了
the following command; pip install --index-url
输入以下命令 pip install --index-url
https://test.pypi.org/simple dsnd_probability.
https://test.pypi.org/simple dsnd_probability.
This says to pip install the package from the test repository website.
这个命令是使用 pip 从测试存储库中安装软件包
It looks like it installed successfully.
看起来安装成功了
Assuming that everything goes well and you're ready to
假设一切顺利
upload the package to the regular PyPi repository,
你已经准备好将包上传到常规的 PyPI 存储库
here's how you can do that.
以下是操作流程
Type twine upload dist/*,
输入 twine upload dist/*
enter your username, your password.
输入你的用户名 密码
Now, let's check on the regular PyPi repository website if everything uploaded.
现在检查一下常规的 PyPI 存储库网站上是否完全上传
I'm going to login. It looks like everything uploaded here as well.
登陆一下 看起来都上传成功了
Remember, we already installed the package from the test website.
注意 我们已经在 test 网站上安装过这个包了
So, I'm going to uninstall it.
所以我要先卸载
Since the package is now also on the regular repository,
因为这个软件包已经在常规存储库中了
I can pip install directly.
我可以直接 pip install
I just write pip install and then the name of the package.
只需要输入 pip install 加上软件包名称
It looks like everything installed correctly.
看起来都正确安装了
Now, I'm going to see if I can use it in a Python program.
现在我要看看 Python 程序中是否可以使用
I'm going to open a new terminal window and I'm going to open a Python interpreter,
打开一个新的终端窗口 进入 Python 解释器
and now I'm going to say from
现在输入 from dsnd_probability import Gaussian, Binomial
So far so good. If I say Gaussian(10,7),
现在一切顺利 输入 Gaussian(10,7)
hit Enter then it's made a Gaussian object with mean 10 and standard deviation seven.
点击回车 然后代码就创建了一个均值为 10 标准偏差为 7 的 Gaussian 对象
If I type Binomial(0.4, 25),
如果我输入 Binomial(0.4, 25)
hit Enter it gives me the mean standard deviation,
点击回车就显示出了均值、标准偏差、
probability, and number of samples.
概率和样本数量
So, it looks like it worked.
看起来代码可以正常运行
What I've shown you is the very basics for getting something up and running with PyPi.
目前展示的是使用 PyPI 设置并运行的基础操作
If you're going to upload the package made in this lesson,
如果你要上传这节课上构建的软件包
make sure you use a different package name than dsnd_probability,
确保你使用的是与 dsnd_probability 不同的名称
otherwise, you won't be able to upload the package
否则不能成功上传
because the name will conflict with the package I just uploaded.
因为会跟我刚刚上传的包名产生冲突
Also, realize that in the package name I used
另外 注意一下软件包名中我使用的是下划线 _
underscore but if you go back to the PyPi website the package gets named with a dash.
但是返回到 PyPI 网站上 名称会变成短横线 -
So that's something to be aware of as well.
这也是需要注意的内容
When you're pip installing,
当使用 pip 安装的时候
you'll have to use the dash.
你需要使用短横线 -
But then, when you're using it in the Python interpreter or in your program,
但是 当你在 Python 解释器或程序中使用该包的时候
you'd use the underscore.
你要使用下划线
Now, it's your turn.
现在轮到你了
Follow the instructions in this video and try uploading your own package to PyPi.
跟随视频中的指导说明 尝试将你自己的软件包上传到 PyPI 上